<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pipelines on pypyr</title><link>https://pypyr.io/docs/pipelines/</link><description>Recent content in pipelines on pypyr</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pypyr.io/docs/pipelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>pipeline yaml structure</title><link>https://pypyr.io/docs/pipelines/pipeline-structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pypyr.io/docs/pipelines/pipeline-structure/</guid><description>pipeline yaml structure permalink pypyr pipeline format permalinkA pipeline is a .yaml file. pypyr uses YAML version 1.2.
Save pipelines wherever you please. To run a pipeline, execute pypyr pipelinename from the directory where you saved pipelinename.yaml
# This is an example showing the anatomy of a pypyr pipeline# A pipeline should be saved as {working dir}/mypipelinename.yaml.# Run the pipeline from {working dir} like this: pypyr mypipelinename# optional. set this to pass cli arguments to the pipeline.</description></item><item><title>pipeline look-up order</title><link>https://pypyr.io/docs/pipelines/lookup-order/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pypyr.io/docs/pipelines/lookup-order/</guid><description>pipeline look-up order permalink the working directory permalinkpypyr first looks for pipelines, any custom steps &amp;amp; other code in the current working directory. This is the directory from which you invoke pypyr.
Simply put, by default, this is the directory you&amp;rsquo;re currently in when you invoke pypyr from the cli.
You can change the default working directory by passing the --dir flag to pypyr CLI. pypyr will use whatever path you specify in --dir as the working directory base path.</description></item><item><title>built-in pipelines</title><link>https://pypyr.io/docs/pipelines/builtin-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pypyr.io/docs/pipelines/builtin-pipelines/</guid><description>Built-in pipelines permalinkpypyr comes with with some basic pipelines out of the box. These don&amp;rsquo;t do much, nor can they: the whole idea is for you to write your own awesome pipelines because it so so easy!
pipeline description how to run donothing Does what it says. Nothing. pypyr donothing echo Echos context value echoMe to output. pypyr echo text goes here pypyrversion Prints the python cli version number.</description></item></channel></rss>