<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>debug on pypyr</title><link>https://pypyr.io/topics/debug/</link><description>Recent content in debug on pypyr</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 21:20:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pypyr.io/topics/debug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>pypyr.steps.assert</title><link>https://pypyr.io/docs/steps/assert/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pypyr.io/docs/steps/assert/</guid><description>pypyr.steps.assert permalink stop pipeline execution if condition false permalinkAssert that something is True or equal to something else. The step raises an exception of type AssertionError if the assertion fails.
You can express an assert in three different ways:
- name:pypyr.steps.assertcomment:evaluates `assert` as truthyin:assert:&amp;#39;{evaluateMe}&amp;#39;- name:pypyr.steps.assertcomment:evaluate `this` as truthyin:assert:this:&amp;#39;{evaluateMe}&amp;#39;- name:pypyr.steps.assertcomment:assert that two things are equalin:assert:this:&amp;#39;{complexThing1}&amp;#39;equals:&amp;#39;{complexThing2}&amp;#39;The first two mostly do the same thing, so use whichever pleases your eye more. The only difference is in how pypyr processes mappings for truthy.</description></item><item><title>description decorator</title><link>https://pypyr.io/docs/decorators/description/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 20:35:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pypyr.io/docs/decorators/description/</guid><description>description permalink provide step status output permalinkdescription is text that prints to the output when the pipeline runs. This is useful to provide operators with visibility of pipeline progress, especially where steps themselves do not provide any output.
The description outputs at NOTIFY - 25 level. This means you will see it by default. If you want to suppress description output, run pypyr with --log higher than 25.
If you are looking to annotate your pipeline in a way that does not print to runtime output use comment instead.</description></item><item><title>pypyr.steps.debug</title><link>https://pypyr.io/docs/steps/debug/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 12:03:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pypyr.io/docs/steps/debug/</guid><description>pypyr.steps.debug permalink debug the context permalinkPretty print the context to output.
Print the pypyr context to the pypyr output. This is likely to be the console. This may assist in debugging when trying to see what values are what.
debug prints to the INFO (20) log-level. This means you won&amp;rsquo;t see debug output unless you specify pypyr mypype --log 20 or lower value for log. If you have values you that always want to print to output, echo is the more natural step to use.</description></item></channel></rss>